Finding aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) Films and Videotapes, 1930s and 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library
- Series FF, Film File
  - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248]
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248]; (Film footage of several psychological and physiological experiments on monkeys, rats, and rabbits conducted by University of Michigan researchers. Include shots of laboratories and scientific equipment and researchers at work.)
      - Original:, 16mm film
    - Psychology Experiment, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-a]; (Devalois.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM researcher Russell Devalois. Features: Russell Devalois)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-b]; (Domino.; Footage of an experiment conducted by Edward Domino of the UM Medical School Department of Pharmacology. Features: Edward Domino, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-c]; (Coombs.; Footage of an experiment conducted by UM psychology professor Clyde Coombs. Features: Clyde H. Coombs, UM-Psych.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-d]; (McCleary, Meyers.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM professors Robert McCleary and Muriel Meyers. Features: Robert McCleary, UM-Psych ;Muriel Meyers, UM-Med.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-e]; (Olds.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM psychology professor James Olds. Features: James Olds, UM-Psych.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-f]; (Walker.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM psychology professor Edward Walker. Features: Edward Walker, UM-Psych.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments, circa 1956; [851831-FF-248-g]; (Footage of experiments on brain cells conducted by UM psychology professors.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
  - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-1]; (Twelve reels of film negatives, consists of documentary footage of "Operation Deep Freeze," a scientific expediting to Antarctica. Shot by UM Television Center Staff. Includes footage of camp at "Little America", experiments, and scenery, sea voyage, and Antarctic scenes.)
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-1]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 981, 00:27:17
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-1.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-2]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 959, 00:26:41
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-2.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-3]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1037, 00:28:50
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-3.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-4]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 878, 00:24:33
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-4.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-5]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1038, 00:28:52
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-5.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-6]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1055, 00:29:20
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-6.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-7]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1099, 0030:32
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-7.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-8]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 986, 00:27:26
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-8.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-9]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1076, 0029:55
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-9.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-10]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1079, 00:30:00
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-10.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-11]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1120, 00:31:07
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-11.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, [851831-FF-249-12]
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1234, 00:34:11
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
  - Ford Donation, [851831-FF-250]; (Two reels of magnetic sound track of press conference and ceremony announcing gift of Fairlane Mansion from Ford Motor Company to the University of Michigan for establishment of the UM Dearborn Campus. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, sot;sot, 900;900
  - Arms Control Conference, (Films #283 - 297 consist of interview footage with participants in the first international symposium on arms control sponsored by the University of Michigan. Participants included government officials, representatives of defense contractors, academic specialists in disarmament research, and peace activists. Some of this footage was incorporated into the Series B programs "Report on Arms Control." Most of the films include negatives, workprints and magnetic sound tracks.)
    - Arms Control: McNaughton, [851831-FF-283-a]; (McNaughton.; Defense Department official discusses Pentagon weapons planning and arms control. Features: John T. McNaughton)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 540;540
    - Arms Control: McNaughton, [851831-FF-283-b]; (McNaughton.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 206;206
    - Arms Control: Hudson, [851831-FF-284-a]; (Publisher of "World Peace Report" discusses efforts to promote and disseminate scholarly research in the field of peace studies.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil;sot, 410;410;410
    - Arms Control: Hudson, [851831-FF-284-b]; (Hudson.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 195;195
    - Arms Control: Aaron, [851831-FF-285]; (Aaron. Director of Arms Control at the Pentagon discusses the arms negotiation process.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot, 265;500;500
    - Arms Control: Karpov, [851831-FF-286-a]; (Karpov.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp, b/w, sil;sot, 575;400
    - Arms Control: Karpov, [851831-FF-286-b]; (Karpov.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 200;200
    - Arms Control: Taylor, [851831-FF-287-a]; (Taylor.; Chairman of the National Research Council on Peace Studies talks about the council's activities and the role of peace organizations in the peace and disarmament movement.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot, 500;500
    - Arms Control: Taylor, [851831-FF-287-b]; (Taylor.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 205;205
    - Arms Control: Morse, [851831-FF-288]; (Morse.; Member of the Long Range Planning Group of the Aero-Jet Corp., a major defense contractor, gives a weapons industry's perspective on the arms control process and the possible economic and social ramifications of disarmament.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 400;400
    - Arms Control: Foster, [851831-FF-289-a]; (Foster. First director of the U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency discusses the founding and purpose of the agency. Features: William C. Foster)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp.neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil;sot, 150;250;250
    - Arms Control: Foster, [851831-FF-289-b]; (Foster.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot;sot, 20;150;20;150
    - Arms Control: Bechoefer, [851831-FF-290]; (Bechoefer.; A State Department official with long experience negotiating with the Russians discusses the process of arms control negotiation. Features: Bernard Bechoefer)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sof;sot, 150;200;200
    - Arms Control: Melman, 1, [851831-FF-291-a]; (Melman. Interview with arms control expert and Pentagon critic Seymor Melman on the impact of the arms race on international affairs and the U.S. economy. Features: Seymour Melman)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 183;183
    - Arms Control: Melman, 1, [851831-FF-291-b]; (Melman.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil;sot, 250;250;250
    - Arms Control: Melman, 2, [851831-FF-292-a]; (Melman.; Arms control expert and Pentagon critic Seymour Melman discusses the adverse effects of the arms race on the U.S. economy and the country's balance of payments and emphasizes the political and economic motives for disarmament.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 205;205
    - Arms Control: Melman, 2, [851831-FF-292-b]; (Melman.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 205;205
    - Arms Control: Lentz, [851831-FF-293-a]; (Lentz.; A peace activist and former university professor discusses his involvement in the disarmament movement following World War II. Features: Ed Lentz)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 472;472
    - Arms Control: Lentz, [851831-FF-293-b]; (Lentz.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 208;208
    - Arms Control; Phelps, [851831-FF-294-a]; (Phelps.; Director of the Institute for Defense Analysis, discusses the role of academic research in arms development and the disarmament process.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 20;150
    - Arms Control: Phelps, [851831-FF-294-b]; (Phelps.;)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot, 20;150;50
    - Arms Control: Lough, [851831-FF-295]; (Lough.; Sound track only, UM professor Thomas Lough, on leave with the U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency discusses his work with the agency.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot, 200;250;250
    - Arms Control: Lough, [851831-FF-295-b]; (Lough.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 150;100
    - Arms Control: Matteson, [851831-FF-296-a]; (Matteson; A policy analyst for the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency discusses his research and work for the agency.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp/neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 171;171
    - Arms Control: Matteson, [851831-FF-296-b]; (Matteson.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 250;250
    - Arms Control: Humphrey, [851831-FF-297]; (Humphrey. Senator Hubert Humphrey discusses the genesis of the U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency and the politics involved in its establishment. Features: Hubert Humphrey)
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp;wp;neg, b/w;b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sof, 200;25;250
  - Alumni Film: Michigamua 1941, circa 1941; [851831-FF-298]; (Footage of the Michigamua initiation, includes shots of the members and initiates in Indian costume, in Union Tower, smoking pipe with Pres. Ruthven, and parading through campus. (original footage once held by the Alumni Association)Features: Alexander Ruthven, UM-Pres.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 238, 00:07:15 @ 18fps
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF298.flv
  - Alumni Association: Rope Day 1941 Michigamua, circa 1941; [851831-FF-299]; (Footage of the Michigamua initiation ceremony, ca. 1941. Includes shots of members painting themselves with "war paint", smoking "peace pipe" with Pres. Ruthven, and ceremony at tree near Graduate Library. (orig. footage once held by Alumni Assoc.)Features: Alexander Ruthven, UM-Pres.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 00:08:40 @ 18 fps
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF299.flv
  - Alumni Association: Football and Track, 1938, [851831-FF-300]; (Brief footage of UM football game (Ohio State 1938?), extended footage of marching band performance, crowd shots, fans on the field, and footage of a Big Ten track meet at Ferry Field. (original footage that was once held by the Alumni Association.)Features: Marching Band)
    - Original:, 16mm film
  - Alumni Association: Michigamua 1939, circa 1939; [851831-FF-301]; (Footage of the Michigamua initiation ceremony, ca. 1939. Includes shots of members painting themselves with "war paint", smoking "peace pipe" with Pres. Ruthven, and ceremony at tree near Graduate Library. Features: Alexander Ruthven, UM-Pres.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, color, silent, 180, 00:06:34 @ 18fps
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF301.flv
- AVEC Films
  The Audio Visual Education Center, originally part of the University Extension Division's Visual Education Bureau and mainly a film distribution service, produces a variety of instructional films and promotional films for the university and also produced some on a contract basis for non-university clients.
  - Aging: A Modern Social Achievement, 1957; [851831-AVEC-1]; (Examines changes in American's life expectancy, lifestyle, work and retirement, and planning for an extended prime of life. Features: Clark Tibbits, UM-Geron.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, optical, 00:13:54, Neg. # 156, Pos. # 1
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC1.flv
  - Analog Computer & its Application to Differential Equations, 1963; [851831-AVEC-2]; (Demonstration of the use of the analog computer to solve differential equations. Includes musical segments by pioneer electronic music composers Robert Ashley and Gordan Mummer. Features: Wilfred Kaplan, UM Math)
    - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, optical, 00:28:47, Neg. # 30, Pos. # 23
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC2.flv
  - Angell-Lironess Project, [851831-AVEC-3]; (A University High School (affiliated with UM) class looks at the question of prejudice and discrimination from a sociological point of view and discusses the economics of farming and the knowledge one needs to farm.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:05:01, Pos. # 63
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC3.flv
  - Aortomyocardial Autogenous Vein Grafts, [851831-AVEC-4]; (Film of surgical procedure for vein grafts is demonstrated and explained. This technique was developed at UM and led to the feasibility of heart bypass operations. Dietrich later worked with heart surgeon Micheal DeBakey. Features: Edward Dietrich, St. Joseph Hosp.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:11:36, Pos. # 2
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC4.flv
  - Band Day 1950, [851831-AVEC-5]; (Filmed highlights of the Band Day performances of UM Marching band at half-time of UM football game. Features: Marching Band)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:11:36, Pos #
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC5.flv
  - Band Director, The, 1974; [851831-AVEC-6]; (UM Marching Band Director George Cavender is featured in a look at the work of a university band director, UM Marching Band drills and performances at Rose Parade, Rose Bowl, and Disneyland. Features UM's last all male Band. Film won five awards. Features: George Cavender, UM-Music)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:33:50, Neg. # 33, Pos. # 68
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC6-.flv
  - Baseball Accident, [851831-AVEC-7]
    - Original:, 16mm film, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Pos. # 32
  - Big Difference, The, 1966; [851831-AVEC-8]; (Instructional film on floor care as means of controlling bacterial contamination in hospitals, produced in cooperation with UM Hospital and H.G. Fuller Co. Includes numerous shots of the old University Hospital.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:19:00, Neg. # 72, Pos. # 4
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC8.flv
  - Child Upper Extremity Amputees, 1964; [851831-AVEC-9]; (Physicians from the UM Medical Center's Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation demonstrate various prosthetic devices and adjustments made as a child grows and learns to control his extremities. Features: Leonard Bender, UM-Med.; Gerald O'Oconnor, UM-Med.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:18:37, Neg. # 70, Pos. # 5
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC9.flv
  - Decade of Achievement, 1956; [851831-AVEC-10]; (Hatcher, who worked closely with AVEC on script, discusses the many areas of development and growth at the University of Michigan over the years 1946-1956. Excellent footage of campus buildings, laboratories, classrooms, and student activities. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:19:53, Pos. # 7
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:
  - Design for Independent Living, 1967; [851831-AVEC-11]; (Demonstration of the specialized activities and equipment for daily living by four severely impaired young adults with the goal of attending school away from home. Footage from the UM Med. Center Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Dept. Features: James W. Rae, UM-Med.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:12:05, Neg. # 146, Pos. # 8
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC11.flv
  - Die is Cast, The, 1972; [851831-AVEC-12]; (Looks at the history of metal casting and the development of the casting process. Footage of Ford Motor Co. die casting operation. Winner of Gold Camera Award, U.S. Industrial Film Festival.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Neg. # 191, Pos. # 40
  - Digital Computer Engineering Lab, [851831-AVEC-13]; (Footage of a Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering lab course on the principles of digital logic and computer interfacing technique. Features: Eric Aupperle, UM-Eng.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, sound, 00:14:22, Neg. # 103, Pos. # 9
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC13.flv
  - Engineering Centennial Convocation, 1954; [851831-AVEC-14]; (Footage of activities celebrating the 100th anniversary of the University of Michigan College of Engineering and the dedication of the Mortimer Cooley Memorial Lab, including banquets, speeches, ribbon cuttings, and ceremonies at Michigan Stadium. Features: Harlan Harcher, UM-Pres.; George Brown, UM-Eng.; Wilbur Pierpont, UM-VP; Charles E. Wilson)
    - Original:, 16mm film, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Pos. # 10
  - Excision and Replacement of the Heart, 1963; [851831-AVEC-16]; (Film of a pioneering UM Medical Center surgical procedure to remove and replace the heart of a dog. Berkeley's surgical experiments at the UM contributed to the development of human heart transplant surgery. Features: Kelly Berkeley, UM-Med.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:14:08, Pos. # 53
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC16.flv
  - Fires and Wires, 1965; [851831-AVEC-17]; (Film produced for UM Extension Service and Detroit Edison, a training film for emergency personnel on safety measures for handling electrical powerlines and wires. An award winning film. More prints of this film were sold than any other AVEC title. Features: George W. Williams, UM-TVC)
    - Original:, 16mm film, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Neg. # 105, Pos. # 41
  - First Aid for Head and Neck Injuries in Football, 1976; [851831-AVEC-19]; (Award winning film on the proper first aid techniques in the treatment of head and neck injuries in football. Schneider, an expert on sports injuries, examines the symptoms of various head and spinal cord injuries and the proper treatment for each. Features: Richard C. Schneider, UM-Med.,; Lindsey McClear, UM-Ath.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:21:53, Pos. # 12
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC19.flv
  - First Heart Beat, 1930s; [851831-AVEC-20]; (A look at the development of a chick embryo and its first heart beats. Produced by the UM Anatomy Dept. and Baldwin Bird Laboratory of Cleveland. An early scientific / instructional film. (Part of a series titled Microcinema Studies, silent, b/w.) Features: Bradley Patten, UM-Med.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, optical, 00:23:01, Pos. # 48
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC20.flv
  - First Hundred Years, 1954; [851831-AVEC-21]; (Excerpts from the full production of the same title.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, sound, coa. 00:300::00, Pos. # 11
  - First Hundred Years: Engineering College Centennial, 1954; [851831-AVEC-22]; (A student from first UM engineering course takes a 100 year nap, on waking he is given tour of College of Engineering facilities. Shows labs and classroom scenes, describes variety of research being conducted, footage of distinguished professors. Features: George G. Brown, Louis Baier, Myron Nichols, Walter Lay, A.D. Moore, all UM-Eng.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, sound, 00:43:02, Pos. # 11
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:
  - Goodby to Captain Hook, 1966; [851831-AVEC-23]; (Documents the prostheses available for various levels of arm amputation. Intended for physicians, physical therapists, social workers, and medical students. Winner of Honors Certificate at 1967 American Film Festival. Features: Leonard Bender, UM-Med.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:19:55, Neg. # 153, Pos. # 13
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC23.flv
  - Health is a Circle, circa 1960; [851831-AVEC-24]; (Decribes the work of the University of Michigan Health Service, how it cooperates with other UM units to provide for the safety and health of students. Footage of the old University Hospital. Script by Daniel Waldron, cinematography George Voellmar.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:15:24, Neg. # 124, Pos. # 55
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC24.flv
  - High School Band Day Highlights, 1960; [851831-AVEC-25]; (Events of Band Day at UM, 12000 high school band members perform at half-time at Michigan Stadium. Karl King leads the massed band, 1500 majorettes entertain, UM Marching Band performs a soft-shoe routine. Features: Karl King)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:26:08, Neg. # 71, Pos. # 17
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC25.flv
  - High School Band Day Highlights, [851831-AVEC-26]; (The film won five major awards including the CINE, highest in U.S. for documentary film. Was also selected as U.S. representative in the Vancouver Film Festival.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Pos. # 76
  - High School Band Day Highlights, 1960; [851831-AVEC-27]; (Additional footage of performance of UM marching Band and 38 high school bands at half-time of UM football game. Features: Karl King)
    - Original:, 16mm film, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Pos. # 18
  - Industrial Exhaust Systems, circa 1948; [851831-AVEC-28]; (An early AVEC production in cooperation with College of Engineering and the Michigan Bureau of Industrial Health. Demonstrates the variety and proper use of industrial ventilating systems. Only film known to exist on the topic. Features: 77)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, sound, ca. 00:30:00, Pos. # 49
  - Sequential Logic, 1974; [851831-AVEC-29-2]; (A demonstration of how the power of combinational logic networks is extended to include the capability to store information.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:16:19, Neg. # 48, Pos. # 16
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC29-1.flv
  - Combinational Logic, 1974; [851831-AVEC-29-1]; (Combinational Logic.; A PDP-9 computer graphics system integrated with a digital analysis program is used to demonstrate the operation of the basic digital logic elements. Includes footage of computer hardware.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, color, optical, 00:17:58, Neg. # 79, Pos. # 15
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 7)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-AVEC29-2.flv